{"id":"2017_12","name":"Romans2017_12","memoryVerse":"“For the wages of sin is death, but the gift of God is eternal life in Christ Jesus our Lord.” – Romans 6:23 ","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_12_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 7:1-6.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"7:1-6"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_12_3","questionText":"3. How do these verses build on the truth of the believer’s union with Christ? (See Romans 6:1-11, 14.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:1-11"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"6:14"}]},{"id":"2017_12_4a","questionText":"4. a. From what does Christ’s death free believers, to whom do they now belong and what is their purpose?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_4b","questionText":"4. b. If you are a believer, how are you living out your God-given purpose and freedom, especially in your relation- ships in work, family, community life, etc.?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_5","questionText":"5. Contrast “fruit for God” and “the new way of the Spirit” with “fruit for death” and “the old way of the written code.” (See also John 15:1-5 and Galatians 5:16-23.) Where do you see these patterns in your life? ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"John","verse":"15:1-5"},{"book":"Galatians","verse":"5:16-23"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 7:7-13. Note: Christians differ about whether Romans 7:7-25 refers to Paul’s life before or after Jesus saved him.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"7:7-13"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_12_6","questionText":"6. From verses 7-13, what does the law do for people, and how does sin use the law against people?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_7","questionText":"7. How does sin deceive you and harm your mind, emotions or body? What does sin reveal about your understanding of God and how will you respond to what He is showing you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 7:14-20.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"7:14-20"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_12_8","questionText":"8. Explain how the law is “spiritual” and why Paul describes himself as “unspiritual.”","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_9","questionText":"9. How would you explain Paul’s struggle in these verses to your family or others you want to help grow in Christ?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_10","questionText":"10. What do you do that you do not want to do, and what good do you not do that you really want to do?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 7:21-25.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"7:21-25"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_12_11","questionText":"11. Describe Paul’s distress over sin in these verses. ","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_12a","questionText":"12. a. How does Paul answer the question he asked in verse 24?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_12b","questionText":"12. b. Why is Paul’s answer the only true help for those who live under the burden of the law as well as those who tend to lawless living?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_13","questionText":"13. Can you share a time distress over sin led you to desperate prayer, and how might Romans 6 and 7 help you pray about your ongoing struggle with sin?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 7:1-25.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"7:1-25"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_12_14","questionText":"14. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_12_15","questionText":"15. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 7","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}